# Ilya Biryukov

Front End Developer (last revisited on 01/15/2016)

E-mail: uncle.funkay@gmail.com

Phone: +7 918 211-37-92

Skype: buzz\_KillingtOn (skype:buzz\_KillingtOn?chat)

GitHub: uncleF (https://github.com/uncleF)

## **Profile**

Front end developer with a computer science degree, 8 years of experience and deep understanding of modern development process and its challenges. Experienced in prototyping and developing user interfaces (sites, apps, emails, IPTV, interactive expo booths, etc.). Have some experience in project management and developing native apps for the iOS and Android. Obsessed with efficient development workflow, personal productivity and constant growth as front end developer.

- Able to complete projects fast and efficient.
- Good problem solving and collaborative skills.
- Rapid learner.
- Write clean and comprehensive code.
- Staying on the bleeding edge of front end development.
- Conversational English

# **Areas of Expertise**

- Responsive Web Design
- Mobile Web Development
- Single Page Web App Development

- E-mail Development
- IPTV UI Development
- Landing Page Development
- UI/UX in Modern Websites
- Usability
- · Cross-browser Compatibility
- Front End Performance Optimization
- Critical Rendering Path Optimization
- Progressive Enhancement / Graceful Degradation
- Accessibility
- Standards Compliance
- Web Content Management
- Project Management

#### **Skills**

- HTML5, CSS3 (Sass), JavaScript (JQuery, Backbone.js, Three.js, etc.), SVG (Snap.svg, Raphael)
- Front end performance and accessibility audit (npm, RubyGems, standalone and web apps)
- Node.js (npm, Grunt, Bower), XML
- Unity
- PHP, SQL
- Java, Objective-C

# **Tools**

- My own open development tool (https://github.com/uncleF/TemplateX) (miniframework) for rapid project workflow setup
- Sublime Text, Eclipse, Xcode, Android Studio
- Emmet, Grunt, Bower, Gulp, Apache Ant
- Adobe Photoshop, Sketch, Pixelmator, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Flash,

- Ghostlab, Litmus (https://litmus.com)
- Basecamp, InVision, Megaplan, Toggl Desktop
- Git, GitHub (https://github.com/), BitBucket (https://bitbucket.org/)
- Wordpress, Drupal

# **Past Employment**

#### Freelance

March 2014 - Currently

### Front End Developer & Consultant

- Developed multiple websites and applications.
- Worked as a volunteer for the FBK (Anti-Corruption Foundation)
   (http://fbk.info/). Had to work on (extremly) tight schedule and find solutions for the complex, nontrivial problems.
- Built a Grunt-based template assembling tool for the proprietary landing page generator.
- Consulted multiple clients on front end performance and accessibility.

# Digital-agency Spider Group (http://spider.ru/en/)

February 2008 - March 2014

#### **Senior Front End Developer**

January 2012 - March 2014

- Developed multiple websites and applications. Including high traffic ecommerce site (http://topliga.ru/).
- Developed user interface for the e-commerce iOS app (https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/fingo.-furniture.-try-before/id567070760?mt=8) from scratch.
- Built UI prototyps and developed interfaces for the interactive expo booths.
- Was responsible for setting up development environment and workflow.
- Built several tools for automating development process.
- Consulted co-workers and clients on all matters concerning front end development.
- Gained some experience in project management and native development

for the iOS and Android.

### **Front End Developer**

February 2008 - January 2012

- Developed multiple websites using several CMS developed in-house and out of the box (PHP, Python).
- Worked on high traffic regional information portal (http://www.kuban.ru/).
- Participated in development of interfaces for the interactive expo booths.
- Created numerous marketing e-mail templates.

# Kuban Internet Company (http://kubic.ru/)

December 2006 - August 2007

### **Front End Developer**

- First professional steps as a fully employed front end developer.
- Developed multiple websites using an in-house CMS (Perl-based).
- Briefly worked on two hight traffic projects regional news portal (http://www.yuga.ru/) and social networking site (http://www.diary.ru/).

#### Freelance

**Before December 2006** 

#### Front End Developer

- String of awful sites build for friends.
- First attempts to earn some money.
- ...mistakes were made.

## **Education**

5 years computer science degree from the Kuban State University (http://www.kubsu.ru/en/).

# **Examples**

- http://rosyama.ru/ (http://rosyama.ru/)
- https://fbk.info/ (https://fbk.info/)
- https://20.navalny.com/ (https://20.navalny.com/)

- http://www.domskala.ru/ (http://www.domskala.ru/)
- http://ruport.ru/ (http://ruport.ru/)
- http://зарулем23.pф/ (http://зарулем23.pф/)
- http://optrika.ru/ (http://optrika.ru/)
- https://prokuror.fbk.info/ (https://prokuror.fbk.info/)
- http://www.semeyniy-uzhin.ru/ (http://www.semeyniy-uzhin.ru/)
- http://www.gagarin-catering.ru/ (http://www.gagarin-catering.ru/)
- http://kristall-komfort.ru/ (http://kristall-komfort.ru/)
- http://ir.magnit.com/ (http://ir.magnit.com/)
- http://shans23.ru/ (http://shans23.ru/)
- http://buhtagold.ru/ (http://buhtagold.ru/)
- http://cifra-group.ru/ (http://cifra-group.ru/)
- http://emercit.ru/ (http://emercit.ru/)
- http://buhtagold.ru/content/7/ (http://buhtagold.ru/content/7/)
- http://gsyp.ru/ (http://gsyp.ru/)
- http://gsyp.ru/complex/building/2/ (http://gsyp.ru/complex/building/2/)
- http://dvinuli.ru/ (http://dvinuli.ru/)
- http://gold-age.org/ (http://gold-age.org/)
- http://topliga.ru/ (http://topliga.ru/)
- http://fingo.pro/ (http://fingo.pro/)
- http://idisplay.spider.ru/ (http://idisplay.spider.ru/)
- http://www.arkhyz-jivitsa.ru/landing/ (http://www.arkhyz-jivitsa.ru/landing/)
- http://moscow.arkhyz-visma.ru/landing/ (http://moscow.arkhyz-visma.ru/landing/)